Uthen Thianprateep

Mobile: 086 5630778

Email: Error! Hyperlink reference not valid.

CAREER SUMMARY

IT System administration with more than 20 years of professional experience with several different platforms such as Windows and Linux. Have a wide range of technical skills in systems installation, configuration, upgrading and maintenance. Dynamic extensive experience with security, database management and technical troubleshooting. Committed and passionate with technology and network administration and effective project management skills.

OBJECTIVE

Looking for a new challenging position in IT and Network security for corporations to support a large scale of users.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Expert knowledge of operation systems such as Mac OS, Windows, and Linux.
- Experience in Ciscoworks, DHCP, SNMP, SQL, C++, and Python.
- Networking systems such as LAN, WAN.
- Data warehouse and ETL concept.
- Knowledge about R, Python, PySpark, and shell script.
- Coding application with Hadoop components HDFS, Hive, Sqoop, Flue, etc,
- DevOps, Cloud Technology

EXPERIENCE

IBM Solutions: IT System Administrator.

(Aug 2013 - Aug 2021)

Key responsibilities:

- Responsible for receiving and transmitting the pure and reliable message, tracking vehicles and equipment, and recording other important information applied by ITIL.
- IT system administrator: (windows base).
- Continuously drive to improve processes for improved performance.
- Developed strategy and created metrics to measure the effectiveness of the strategy.
- Performed application monitoring and performance tuning.
- Performed custom application changes in development, validation or equivalent testing environment and production environments.
- Performed operation system software updates, upgrades and patches fix VA report.
- Manage others through convenience rather than use direct authority.
- Performed administration activities such as setting user accounts, roles, access and privileges.

ACHIEVEMENT

- Achieved monthly SLA target agreed between client and IBM team.
- Customer satisfaction with the higher level.

ATOS (Thailand): IT System administration (Mail Support)

(Apr 2011 – Jul 2013)

Key responsibilities:

- Continuously drive to improve processes for improved performance.
- Performed administration activities such as setting user accounts, roles, access and privileges, support incident, service request from customers and generating monthly incident report for supervisor.

Terabyte Net Solution: IT System administrator outsourcing

(Jan 2007 - Mar 2011)

Key responsibilities:

- Continuously drive to improve processes for improved performance.
- Performed administration activities such as setting user accounts, roles access, and privileges, support incident, service request from customer.
- IT implementer.
- Visit customer site, implement HP server product, support onsite for incident.

True Corp: Engineer / IT implementer

(Feb 2003 - Dec 2006)

Key responsibilities:

- Designed and Configured company products.
- Support IT Production for SMB customers based on company products.
- IT System administrator outsourcing.
- Continuously drive to improve processes for improved performance.
- Performed administration activities such as setting user accounts, roles, access, and privileges, support incident, service request from customer.

SVOA Co., LTD

(May 2001 - Jan 2003)

Key responsibilities:

• Provide IT solutions to customer implement and support after implementation for government customer, enterprise business.

CSCI; Support Engineer

(Jan 2001 – Apr 2001)

Key responsibilities:

Installed and support IT production (Desktop, notebook, Printer, etc)

Elec & Eltec Thailand; Engineer

(Jan 2000 – Dec 2000)

Key responsibilities:

Maintenance Engineer, Managed & protection planning for machine on production line

EDUCATION

Kasetsart University	
Bachelor of Engineering, Major:	Electrical (1995 - 1999)

REFEREES

will provide upon request.